Mark Villa Marcos

Blockchain Full Stack Developer

4 +1 979 217 1066

• 2327 Wildbriar Dr, Arlington, TX, US

Dec 4th, 1992

a trayanus1026

S live:.cid.a7ee1867c45b9b61

INTRODUCTION

Ingenious, Determined, and Self-motivated software engineer with 7 years of professional experience who always works as a self-starter, with strong experience in the architecture, development, and maintenance of a wide variety of software. Experienced in the development of a diverse set of products and technologies, which includes e-commerce, NFT marketplaces, performance monitoring/tuning, operating systems, system configuration, groupware, GUI, spreadsheets, database, and blockchain related products, with a deep and clear understanding about full-stack application development and SDLC. I like to study and create new technology and develop secure applications. Well-versed in creating test cases, as well as covering all test conditions and eliminating redundancy and duplications. Additionally successfully identified and resolved a process bottleneck that reduced coding efficiency by up to 30%.

Work Experience

Blockchain Full Stack Engineer

bc.team | 2021.4 – 2023.3

bc.team, one of the leading blockchain development companies, has a plethora of experience in providing blockchain solutions

- Managed a geographically distributed team of 8 developers with operations, priorities, and development goals utilizing Agile techniques such as weekly/bi-weekly scrums.
- Functional specification reviews to ensure consistency and accuracy with the client's needs.
- Experience in architecture and coding of enterprise-grade blockchain applications.
- Strong understanding of cryptography, including asymmetric with public and private keys,
 symmetric, hash functions, encryption, and signatures.
- Expertise in analysis, architecture, and development of blockchain solutions, distributed computing, smart contracts, and dApps on Ethereum blockchain using solidity, Microsoft azure, remix, truffle, hardhat frameworks, ganache, web3.js, metamask, react.js, node.js, and typescript.

Web3 & Smart Contract Engineer

Gocha | 2019.5 – 2021.4 | Remote

Gocha makes it easier for everybody to accept and perform crypto payments through the implementation of efficient and simple-to-use, decentralized payment tools

- Implemented the escrow smart contract using solidity.
- Developed the workpress Web3 Payment Plugin and developed the backend side codebase using node. js and implemented the web3 integration.
- Integrated with Oracle side and zk-snark to secure the offchain data.

Blockchain Full Stack & Test Engineer

ARSR Technologies | 2017.12 – 2019.3 | Remote

ARSR Technologies offers blockchain technology for event management services

- Understand business drivers, goals/objectives, and opportunities and create innovative strategy/vision and solution roadmap/architecture for the implementation.
- Experienced with multiple Blockchain Technology platforms (Ethereum/Hyperledger/Ripple/Solana).
- Work with MERN, MEAN, and MEVN stack for developing applications.
- Responsible for creating Restful web services to server data to the front-end application in JSON format.
- Developed hundreds of smart contracts deployed on the main net, and audited 10+. Redesigned the company site and built it.
- Analyzed business requirements to translate functional requirements into technical requirements and developed web applications using MongoDB, Express, and Golang
- Participated in 300+ code reviews to ensure code quality and receive mentoring from senior developers.
- Gained experience with various web development tools including Bower, NPM, Git, Material design, Gulp, and cloud services like AWS, Azure, GCP, Heroku, and so on.
- Applied hands-on learning and agile development to build full MERN stack applications.
- Implemented Unit and E2E test cases using Jasmine, Jest, Mocha, Grunt, and Node.js.

Web3 & Full Stack Game Engineer

Mobile Reality | 2015.8 – 2017.12 | Onsite

Collect and trade CryptoKitties in one of the world's first blockchain games

- Entailed breeding kittens, raising them, and exchanging them with other players.
- Optimized the transaction gas price on the existing ethereum smart contract and suggested a solution to solve the scalability problem.
- Developed Layer 2 smart contracts using Solidity and implemented the gaming proxy.
- Implemented the web3 integration with frontend and backend.

C & C++, C#, java, unity3D Desktop Program

Freelancer & upwork | 2013.4 – 2015.8 | Onsite

Freelancer and upwork are great job sites that give programmers a lot of development opportunities.

- Participated in the development of office processing programs for Linux and handled the document editor part.
- In the employee management program, I was in charge of attendance management and wage management.
- Participated in the 3D game (similar to Tank war) project and performed the action handling part including the collision case.

Education

- Bachelor of Computer Science
- Nanzan University | 2009.8- 2013.4

Skill

- React.js, Vue.js, Angular.js, Node.js, Django
- Ethereum, Solana, Smart Contract
- TypeScript, Rust, Solidity, Golang, Python
- CI/CD, AWS, Docker
- C, C++, C#, Java, Unity3D